DAVID MALAN: This is CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python.
David Malan：这是CS50的S介绍使用Python语言编程
My name is David Malan.
我叫大卫·马兰
And this is our week on unit tests.
本周是我们进行单元测试的一周
Up until now, we've been writing a lot of code,
到目前为止 我们一直在编写大量代码
and you might have been testing your code by running your program,
您可能一直在通过运行您的程序来测试代码
and passing in some sample inputs, and running it again, and passing
并传入一些样本输入 然后再次运行它 然后传递
in some sample inputs, or you might have been waiting
在一些样本输入中 或者您可能一直在等待
for us to test your code instead.
让我们测试您的代码
But it's actually much better practice to get into the habit sooner
但实际上更好的做法是尽早养成这个习惯
rather than later of testing your own code using code of your own.
而不是稍后使用您自己的代码测试您自己的代码
In fact, whether you're writing a personal project
事实上 无论你是在写一个个人项目
or working in industry, it's very common nowadays to not only write code
或者在工业中工作 如今很常见的不仅仅是编写代码
to solve the problems that you want to solve,
要解决你想要解决的问题
but also to write a little extra code to test the code that you wrote.
还可以编写一些额外的代码来测试您编写的代码
And that's what we're going to focus on today, writing our own test so as
这就是我们今天要关注的 编写我们自己的测试
to be all the more confident, all the more certain,
更加自信 更加确定
that the problems we have been trying to solve are, in fact, solved correctly.
我们一直试图解决的问题实际上得到了正确的解决
So let's rewind a few weeks now to a program we wrote a while back,
现在让我们回到几周前我们编写的一个程序
namely to calculate numbers.
即计算数字
And specifically, we left off with this calculator
具体地说 我们没有使用这个计算器
on trying to compute the power of a number, like x squared
关于试图计算一个数字的幂 比如x的平方
or where x might be two or three or some other number as well.
或者其中x可以是2、3或其他一些数字
Let me go ahead and resurrect that file by going into my terminal window
让我进入终端窗口 继续恢复该文件
here and running again code of calculator.py.
在这里再次运行culator.py的代码
And let me go ahead and pick up where we left off way back when
让我继续 从很久以前我们停止的地方开始
by defining a main function here.
通过在这里定义一个主函数
And then in my main function, I did something like this.
然后在我的主要功能中 我做了这样的事情
I said, x equals int of input.
我说 x等于输入的int
And I ask the user, what's x, question mark?
我问用户 x是什么 问号？
And then I immediately went ahead and printed out something like,
然后我立即开始打印 打印出了这样的东西
x squared is, and then I passed in as a second argument
X的平方是 然后我作为第二个参数传入
to print the result of calling a function called
打印调用名为的函数的结果
square passing in that value, x.
平方传递那个值 x
Now of course, I haven't yet implemented the square function.
当然 现在我还没有实现Square函数
So let's define that as well.
所以让我们也来定义一下
Let me go down a couple of lines and define square.
让我沿着几行来定义正方形
And it takes an argument recall, a parameter that at the time
它需要一个参数调用 这个参数在当时
I called n, for number, so I'll do that again, though I could technically
我给n打了个号码 所以我会再做一次 尽管从技术上讲我可以
choose any name for this variable.
为该变量选择任意名称
And I recall, did this.
我记得 就是这样做的
I returned n times n.
我返回了n乘以n
And there were multiple ways to do this.
有多种方法可以做到这一点
Squaring a number is multiplying it by itself.
对一个数字进行平方就是将其自身相乘
So I could also use other syntax here, but this
所以我也可以在这里使用其他语法 但是这个
is what we ultimately settled on, and then
是我们最终决定的 然后
recall that I ultimately called main in order to kick off
回想一下 我最终调用了Main 以便启动
the process of running this program.
运行该程序的过程
So just as a test manually, let me go ahead and run
因此 就像手动测试一样 让我继续运行
Python of calculator.py and hit Enter.
Python.py并按Enter键
What's x?
X是什么？
Let's start with 2.
让我们从2开始
x squared is 4.
X的平方是4
I think that's correct.
我想这是对的
So let's run it again, just for good measure.
所以让我们再运行一次 只是为了更好地衡量
Python of calculator.py, let's type in 3 for x this time.
Py的Python 这一次让我们输入x的3
X squared is 9.
X的平方是9
And I think that's correct.
我认为这是正确的
And I might be feeling pretty good at this point,
在这一点上我可能感觉很好
and I go off and submit my code to a course,
然后我去把我的代码提交给一个课程
or I post it on the internet for others to use.
或者我把它发布到互联网上 供其他人使用
But I haven't really methodically tested this code.
但我还没有真正系统地测试过这段代码
And it's not necessarily the case that it works entirely.
而且情况并不一定是完全有效的
In fact, I haven't really considered a number of corner cases.
事实上 我还没有真正考虑过一些角落案例
I went with some pretty obvious numbers like 2 and 3, but what about 0?
我用了一些非常明显的数字 比如2和3 但0呢？
What about negative numbers?
那么负数呢？
What about any number of other infinite numbers?
那么任何数量的其他无穷大的数字呢？
We're not going to test an infinite number of inputs
我们不会测试无限数量的输入
to this, because the program would never halt,
对于这一点 因为这个程序永远不会停止
but we should test some representative inputs ultimately.
但我们最终应该测试一些有代表性的投入
But before we do that, let's get into the habit of making sure
但在此之前 让我们养成一个习惯 确保
that main isn't always called.
这条主干道并不总是被称为Main
Let's adopt this habit, again, of doing If__name__=="__main__",
让我们再一次养成这样的习惯 如果__name__==“__main__”
only then should we execute main.
只有到那时 我们才能执行Main
And I'm doing this now proactively, because I
我现在正在积极地做这件事 因为我
want to make sure that when I import my square function, perhaps
我想确保在我导入平方函数时 也许
from another library, from another file, treating it as though it's a library,
从另一个库 从另一个文件 将其视为库
I want to make sure that main is not just automatically called itself.
我希望确保main不会被自动调用
Now what do I want to do from here now that I've
现在我现在想做什么 因为我已经
modified this program as follows?
是否按如下方式修改此程序？
Let's go ahead and write a completely different program whose sole purpose
让我们继续编写一个完全不同的程序 它的唯一目的是
in life is to now test this program.
现在就是在生活中考验这个程序
So I've got my actual calculator and calculator.py.
所以我得到了我的实际计算器和计算器.py
I've readied myself to call main conditionally
我已经准备好有条件地给Main打电话
so that I can safely import one or more things from this file in another file.
这样我就可以安全地将一个或多个内容从此文件导入到另一个文件中
What should that other file be?
另一个文件应该是什么？
By convention, I'm going to create a file that's called test_,
按照惯例 我将创建一个名为test_的文件
and then because the thing I'm testing is this calculator itself,
然后因为我测试的是这个计算器本身
let's call this file test_calculator.py.
让我们将该文件命名为test_culator.py
That's going to give me a new tab, in which I
这将给我一个新的标签 在其中我
can write a brand new program whose purpose in life
我可以写一个全新的程序 它的人生目标
is now specifically to test that program,
现在专门用来测试这个程序
but really that program's specific functionality.
但实际上这是该程序的特定功能
Built into that program is the square function.
该程序内置了Square函数
Let's focus on testing that function.
让我们专注于测试该功能
So how do I access that function in this program?
那么 我如何访问该程序中的功能呢？
Recall that I can import a function from another file
回想一下 我可以从另一个文件导入函数
as though it's a library of my own, a so-called module.
就好像它是我自己的一个库 一个所谓的模块
So I'm going to do this.
所以我要这么做
From calculator, import square.
从计算器中导入正方形
I could go ahead and just import square itself.
我可以继续下去 只需导入Square本身
But then I would have to prefix my use of square recall
但是我必须在我使用的Square recall前面加上前缀
by saying calculator dot everywhere, and it's just a little cleaner
通过说计算器到处都是点 它只是更干净一点
to just import the one function.
来只导入一个函数
And now let me go ahead and do this.
现在让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and define a function called test square.
让我们继续定义一个名为test square的函数
This too is a convention.
这也是一场大会
If you want to test a function called square, your function for testing
如果您想测试一个名为Square的函数 那么您要测试的函数
should be called test_square.
应该称为test_square
Or alternatively, you could do square_test,
或者 您也可以执行Square_test
I'll adopt this convention here.
我将在这里采用这一惯例
Now what kind of tests can we do?
现在我们可以做什么样的测试呢？
I don't dislike the tests I ran earlier, testing x equals 2 and x equals 3.
我不喜欢我之前运行的测试 测试x等于2 x等于3
But every time I want to test my program previously,
但每次我之前想测试我的程序时
I would have to do that manually.
我必须手动完成这项工作
And that's going to get tedious.
这将会变得单调乏味
It's not going to be easy for someone else to test it.
对于其他人来说 测试它并不容易
And if I'm actually working in the real world,
如果我真的在现实世界中工作
it would be nice if I could automatically
如果我能不假思索地
have my program tested again and again by having some automated process run
让我的程序通过运行一些自动化进程来一次又一次地进行测试
my own code.
我自己的代码
So let's do that and take the human ultimately out of the equation.
因此 让我们这样做 并最终将人类排除在方程式之外
So how might I go about testing the square function
那么我该如何开始测试平方函数呢
that I've now imported per line one?
我现在每一行都导入了什么？
In my test square function, why don't I do this?
在我的检验平方函数中 为什么不这样做呢？
If the result of calling square of 2 does not equal 4,
如果调用2的平方的结果不等于4
why don't we go ahead and print an error message,
为什么我们不继续打印一条错误消息
because I know that in the real world, 2 squared should equal 4,
因为我知道在现实世界中 2的平方应该等于4
so if square of 2 does not equal 4, there's a bug in my program.
因此 如果2的平方不等于4 则我的程序中存在错误
There's a bug in my function.
我的函数中有一个错误
I've made a mistake.
我犯了个错误
So let me go ahead and print something like that so I or someone else
所以让我继续打印一些类似的东西 这样我或其他人
knows 2 squared was not 4, for instance.
例如 知道2的平方不是4
So I could print out anything here.
这样我就可以打印出这里的任何东西
What should I maybe next test?
也许下一次我应该做什么测试？
Let's do more than one test.
让我们做不止一次测试
Let's say if the square of 3 does not equal 3 squared 9, then let's go ahead
比方说 如果3的平方不等于3的平方9 那么我们继续
and print out that 3 squared was not 9.
打印出3的平方不是9
So I haven't done any more testing than I did earlier.
所以我没有比之前做更多的测试
But I've baked those two tests, x equals 2 and x equals 3, into my own code
但我已经将x等于2和x等于3这两个测试放入了我自己的代码中
here, so I can now run those tests automatically, if you will.
现在 我可以自动运行这些测试 如果您愿意的话
Now, it's not enough to just define a function called test square.
现在 仅仅定义一个称为检验平方的函数是不够的
I actually, if I want to run this function, need to call it somehow.
实际上 如果我想运行这个函数 需要以某种方式调用它
And our convention for doing that is the same as always.
我们这样做的惯例是一如既往的
In this file too, let me define main.
在这个文件中 也让我定义Main
And main's sole purpose in life is going to be to test square.
而Main在生活中的唯一目标将是测试Square
And now at the bottom of this file, as before,
现在 和以前一样 在这个文件的底部
let me go ahead and adopt my convention of if__name__=="__main__",
让我继续采用我的惯例：if__name__==“__main__”
then go ahead and call main.
然后继续呼叫Main
So a lot of this is just boilerplate.
因此 这些都只是例行公事
We've seen this before, defining a main function
我们以前见过这种情况 定义了一个主函数
and calling a function to kick off some process,
并调用一个函数来启动某个进程
now adding the conditional at the bottom of the file
现在在文件的底部添加条件
to make sure I'm only conditionally calling main, just in case I import
以确保我只是有条件地调用main 以防我导入
anything from this file elsewhere.
其他地方的这份文件里有没有发现
So let's see.
让我们来看看
Let's go ahead and test my code now.
现在让我们继续测试我的代码
Let me go ahead and run test_calculator Python and hit Enter,
让我继续运行test_culator Python并按Enter键
and nothing outputs.
而且什么都不会产生
Nothing outputs.
什么都没有输出
But I think it's OK.
但我觉得这没问题
I think no output is good, because look at my test square function.
我认为没有输出是好的 因为看看我的测试平方函数
I'm not printing anything if all seems well.
如果一切顺利 我不会打印任何东西
So let's demonstrate as much by going back to my calculator,
所以让我们回到我的计算器来演示一下
and let me break it.
让我来打破它
Let me introduce a bug.
让我来介绍一个错误
Maybe I didn't even get it right the first time.
也许我第一次都没答对
Maybe my code originally looked like this.
也许我的代码最初是这样的
I wasn't thinking.
我当时没在想
I forgot my squares.
我忘了带我的方格
And so I thought that the square of a number is n plus n,
所以我认为一个数字的平方是n加n
instead of n times n, so a reasonable mistake to make,
而不是n乘以n 所以犯了一个合理的错误
perhaps arithmetically.
也许是算术上的
Let me now go back to my test calculator,
现在让我回到我的测试计算器
which I'm not going to change, but I am going to rerun it,
我不会改变它 但我会重新运行它
python of test_calculator.py.
测试计算器.py的Python
I'm going to cross my fingers here, but for naught, I'm
我要在这里祈祷 但无缘无故 我
going to see immediately that 3 squared was not 9.
马上就会发现3的平方不是9
Now what is it?
现在是什么事？
Let's see, when your tests fail, how can we put our finger on what's wrong?
让我们看看 当你的测试失败时 我们怎么能指出哪里出了问题？
It's a little interesting that I completely broke my square function,
有点有趣的是 我完全破坏了我的平方函数
and yet only one of these tests is failing.
然而 这些测试中只有一项失败了
It looks like this test, lines 9 and 10, is fine,
这个测试 第9行和第10行 看起来没问题
because I'm not seeing that output.
因为我看不到这样的结果
But of course these two lines, this test,
但是当然这两条线 这个测试
is failing, because 3 squared is not 9 when I'm using plus.
失败了 因为当我使用加号时 3的平方不是9
So just to be clear here, why is my function only partially broken,
所以在这里澄清一下 为什么我的功能只有部分损坏
just to be clear.
我只想说清楚
Why am I seeing only I error instead of two,
为什么我只看到我的错误 而不是两个
even though the square function is now mathematically broken?
即使平方函数现在在数学上被破坏了？
SPEAKER 1: Because 2 plus 2 is 4.
演讲者1：因为2加2等于4
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, it's as simple as that.
大卫·马兰：是的 就这么简单
I just got lucky that 2 plus 2 is the same thing as 2 times 2.
我只是很幸运 2加2等于2乘以2
So this is one of those corner cases, and this
所以这是一个角落里的案例 而这个
is why it's good to be in the habit of not just testing one thing,
这就是为什么养成不只测试一件事的习惯是好的
but test several and make sure you're covering your bases, so to speak.
但测试几个 并确保您的基础 可以这么说
So I got lucky here.
所以我在这里很幸运
And that explains why I'm seeing only I error,
这就解释了为什么我只看到了I错误
even though the function itself is flawed, but let me propose that there's
尽管函数本身是有缺陷的 但让我建议
another way we could do this, because honestly,
另一种我们可以做的方式 因为老实说
if I extrapolate from this simple example, running not just two tests
如果我从这个简单的例子推断 运行的不仅仅是两个测试
but 3, or 4, or 10, or 20 tests, you can imagine that, my God,
但是3个、4个、10个或20个测试 你可以想象 天哪
the code is going to get so much more complicated than the function itself.
代码将变得比函数本身复杂得多
Already, look, in calculator.py, the function in question is two lines long.
看 在culator.py中 有问题的函数已经有两行长了
And yet in test_calculator, the code in question is five lines long.
然而 在TEST_COMPUATOR中 有问题的代码有五行长
I've written more code to test my code than I actually wrote original code.
我编写了比实际编写的原始代码更多的代码来测试我的代码
So the fewer lines of code we can write when testing code,
因此 我们在测试代码时可以编写的代码行越少
I think the more likely you and I are to do it,
我觉得你和我越有可能这么做
because it's going to be literally a little
因为从字面上讲 这将是一种
less work and just fewer opportunities for mistakes.
工作量更少 犯错的机会也更少
So what's another approach I can take here?
那么 我还可以采取什么其他方法呢？
it turns out in Python, there is another keyword that we haven't yet used,
事实证明 在Python中 还有一个我们还没有使用过的关键字
which is this here, assert.
这就是这里 断言
Assert is a keyword in Python and some other languages as well
Assert是Python和其他一些语言中的关键字
that allow you to do exactly that, as in English, to assert
它允许你这样做 就像在英语中 断言
that something is true, to sort of boldly claim that something is true.
某件事是真的 大胆地宣称某事是真的
And if it is, nothing's going to happen.
如果是这样的话 什么都不会发生
No errors are going to appear on the screen.
屏幕上不会出现任何错误
But if you assert something in Python, and it is not true, that is,
但如果你用Python语言断言某件事 而这不是真的 那就是
the thing you're insert asserting, a Boolean expression, is false,
您要插入的断言是一个布尔表达式 它是假的
you're actually going to see some kind of error on the screen.
实际上 您将在屏幕上看到某种错误
So let's go ahead and try this new keyword as follows.
因此 让我们继续尝试这个新关键字 如下所示
Let me go back to my code here.
让我在这里回到我的代码
And just to make it a little simpler, let
为了让事情简单一点 让我们
me propose that I use this new keyword as follows.
我建议我使用这个新的关键字 如下所示
Let me simply assert that the square of 2 should equal 4.
让我简单地断言 2的平方应该等于4
So I've changed my logic.
所以我改变了我的逻辑
Instead of checking for not equals, I'm now
而不是检查不等于 我现在是
asserting very loudly that it should equal 4.
非常大声地断言它应该等于4
And then on one additional line, let me do the other test,
然后在另一行 让我做另一个测试
assert that the square of 3 equals equals 9.
断言3的平方等于9
And that's it, no indented print.
就是这样 没有缩进的指纹
I'm just going to assert more simply these two
我只想更简单地断言这两个
things that I want to be true.
我想要成真的事情
Let me go ahead now, with calculator.py still broken.
现在让我继续 计算器.py仍然是坏的
I'm still using plus accidentally, instead of multiplication.
我还是不小心用了加号 而不是乘法
Let me go ahead now and run Python of test calculator.py,
现在让我继续运行测试计算器.py的Python
crossing my fingers as always, but it's not going to go well this time.
像往常一样祈祷 但这一次不会很顺利
A whole lot of errors seem to appear on the screen.
屏幕上似乎出现了一大堆错误
And if I scroll up here for this traceback,
如果我滚动到这里进行回溯
we'll see that the thing that failed was this line here, assert square(3) == 9.
我们将看到失败的是这里的这一行 断言Square(3)==9
Now unfortunately, when you're using the assert keyword,
不幸的是 当您使用ASSERT关键字时
it's not terribly user friendly.
它的用户友好性不是很好
It shows you the files and the line numbers involved,
它向您显示所涉及的文件和行号
but it does show you the specific line of code that failed,
但它确实向您显示了失败的特定代码行
the assertion that failed, so to speak.
可以说 这一断言失败了
It's now kind of up to you and me to infer from this, wait a minute,
现在就靠你和我来推断了 等等
why is the square root 3 not equal to 9?
为什么平方根3不等于9？
So it's not super user friendly, but honestly, it
所以它不是超级用户友好型的 但老实说 它
was half as much code for me to write.
是我要写的代码的一半
It's just two lines, instead of those previous four.
只有两行 而不是之前的四行
But notice this little remnant down here.
但请注意下面这一小块残留物
This was an assertion error.
这是一个断言错误
And we have seen errors before.
我们以前也见过错误
We've seen errors before when we've made other mistakes in our code.
当我们在代码中犯了其他错误时 我们以前也见过错误
And in the past, what was our solution for catching those errors?
在过去 我们捕捉这些错误的解决方案是什么？
How do we catch errors that seem to resemble this,
我们如何捕捉看起来像这样的错误
even though we've not seen this one before?
即使我们以前没见过这个？
SPEAKER 2: Try and except.
演讲者2：试着排除
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, in Python, we can use the try and except keywords
David Malan：是的 在Python中 我们可以使用Try和Except关键字
to try to do something, optimistically, except if something goes wrong,
试着乐观地做某事 除非出了什么差错
do something else instead.
相反 做些其他的事情
So this is a step forward, in that I can at least catch this error.
所以这是向前迈出的一步 因为我至少可以捕捉到这个错误
But it's going to be perhaps a step backward, in that I'm
但这可能会是一种倒退 因为我
going to end up writing, I'll admit in advance, a little more code instead.
我要提前承认 最终要写的是更多的代码
So let me go ahead and try this.
所以 让我继续试一试
Let me go back into my code here.
让我在这里回到我的代码
And instead of just asserting, blindly, let
与其盲目地断言 不如让
me go ahead, as Tola proposed, and try to do this first assertion,
我继续 按照托拉的提议 试着做第一个断言
except if there is an assertion error, like we saw a moment ago, then go ahead
除非出现断言错误 就像我们刚才看到的那样 然后继续
and print out something more user friendly
并打印出更方便用户的内容
that explains what actually failed.
这就解释了什么才是真正失败的
2 squared was not 4.
2的平方不是4
And let me go ahead similarly and try to assert that the square of 3
让我以同样的方式继续 试着断言3的平方
equals 9, except if there's an assertion error there, in which case,
等于9 除非存在断言错误 在这种情况下
I'm going to print out, more user friendly, 3 squared was not 9.
我要打印出来 更人性化 3的平方不是9
So I've taken a step forward, but also a step back,
所以我前进了一步 但也后退了一步
because now I have more code.
因为现在我有了更多的代码
But I have at least introduced assertions and exceptions
但我至少引入了断言和例外
in a manner consistent with how we've seen in the past.
以一种与我们过去所见一致的方式
When something goes wrong, you actually see an exception raised.
当出现问题时 您实际上会看到异常被引发
Let me go ahead and run this version of the program now instead.
现在让我继续运行这个版本的程序
Python of test calculator.py, crossing my fingers,
测试计算器.py的巨蟒 祈祷我的手指
it's still failed, because I'm seeing output.
它仍然失败 因为我看到了输出
But we're back to at least user friendly output.
但我们至少回到了用户友好的输出
So that's at least progress in some way here.
因此 这至少是在某种程度上的进步
But it's, again, more code than might have been ideal.
但同样 它的代码可能比理想的要多
And in fact, if we continue this further, what if we actually
事实上 如果我们继续这样做 如果我们真的
want to add additional test cases here as well?
还想在这里添加额外的测试用例吗？
It seems like we might end up writing way more code than would be ideal.
看起来我们最终可能会写出比理想中多得多的代码
For instance, I'm testing 2 and 3 now.
例如 我现在正在测试2和3
I should probably test some negative numbers as well.
我也应该测试一些负数
So why don't I go ahead and add in, for instance-- let me go ahead
所以我为什么不继续加进去呢 比如说--让我继续
and copy and paste this.
复制粘贴这个
Let me try to assert that the square root of negative 2 equals
让我试着断言负2的平方根等于
equals 4, which should be the case mathematically.
等于4 数学上应该是这样
And if not, let me go ahead and change this
如果没有 让我继续改变这个
to say negative 2 squared was not 4.
负2的平方不是4
And let me go ahead and copy paste this again,
让我继续复制粘贴这个
test another negative number, just for good measure.
测试另一个负数 只是为了更好地衡量
Let's test the square root of negative 3, which should equal 9.
让我们测试负3的平方根 它应该等于9
But if it doesn't, let's go ahead and say that negative 3 squared was not 9.
但如果不是 我们继续假设负3的平方不是9
And just to think aloud here, what might be another good value to test?
在这里大声思考一下 还有什么值得测试的？
I've tried 2.
我试过两次
I've tried 3.
我试过三个
I've tried negative 2.
我试过负2
I've tried negative 3.
我试过负3
I can't try infinite numbers.
我不能尝试无限的数字
But there's at least something that's a little
但至少有一点
different in between those values.
这些价值观之间的差异
Let's try 0.
让我们试试0
0 is an interesting case too, just in case something might be wrong.
0也是一个有趣的例子 以防万一
And why 0?
为什么是0？
I'm just going with instincts here.
我只是凭直觉
Odds are positive numbers are generally going to behave the same.
正数的概率一般都是一样的
Negative numbers might generally behave the same.
负数的行为通常是相同的
0 might be a little anomalous.
0可能有点反常
There's no science to it necessarily, but rather considering for yourself
这不一定是科学 而是你自己考虑一下
based on your own experience, what are the potential corner cases based
根据您自己的经验 潜在的极端情况是基于什么
on the function you're trying to test?
你要测试的功能上的区别吗
I'm trying to test something mathematical,
我在试着测试一些数学问题
so I want to test representative values.
所以我想测试代表性的值
So let me go ahead and paste in one more try except block.
所以让我继续粘贴在一个尝试除了块
Let's assert that the square of 0 should equal 0.
让我们断言0的平方应该等于0
And if not, I'll say something explanatory, like 0 squared was not 0.
如果不是 我会解释一下 比如0的平方不是0
Now if I go ahead and run this, Python of test_calculator.py, and hit Enter,
现在如果我继续运行这个 Python的test_calculator.py 然后按Enter
now I see multiple errors.
现在我看到了多个错误
And this is interesting.
这很有趣
It's a bit of a clue, because notice that some, but not all,
这是一条线索 因为注意到一些 但不是全部
of these assertions are failing.
这些断言都失败了
The 1 for 2 squared is apparently OK, as we noted earlier.
正如我们前面提到的 1比2的平方显然是可以的
Recall that 2 squared happens to be 2 plus 2.
回想一下 2的平方正好是2加2
So that bug doesn't really throw off our test,
所以这个错误并不会影响我们的测试
but it's a good thing we tested for 3.
但这是一件好事 我们测试了3
It's a good thing we tested for negative 2 and negative 3,
幸好我们检测到了负2和负3
because all of those tests caught this error.
因为所有这些测试都发现了这个错误
The 0 test did not notice, because 0 squared is, of course, 0, but 0 plus 0
0测试没有注意到 因为0的平方当然是0 但0加0
is 0.
为0
So we're getting lucky or unlucky there, depending
因此 我们在那里变得幸运或不幸 取决于
on how you view the glass as half full or half empty here.
在这里 你如何看待杯子是半满还是半空
We at least by way of having multiple tests caught this mistake somehow.
我们至少通过多次测试以某种方式发现了这个错误
So it would be nice, though, if we weren't writing so much darn code here,
所以 如果我们不在这里写那么多该死的代码 那就太好了
because notice what I've done.
因为注意我的所作所为
I have try, except, try, except.
我试过 除了试过 试过
I have all of these assertions.
我有所有这些断言
I have a main function.
我有一个主要的功能
I have this if conditional at the bottom of my file.
我在我的文件底部有这个有条件的
Honestly, who's going to want to write 31 lines of code
老实说 谁会想要写31行代码
now just to test a two line function?
现在来测试一个两行函数？
No one's going to write test code like this
没有人会写出这样的测试代码
if we're all writing so much more code to do the actual testing.
如果我们都要编写更多的代码来进行实际测试
So people have solved this problem.
所以人们已经解决了这个问题
If you are in the habit of testing your code a lot, or wanting to,
如果您习惯于大量测试代码 或者想要这样做
if I'm in the habit of wanting to test my code a lot,
如果我养成了经常测试代码的习惯
if everyone else in the real world is in this habit of wanting
如果现实世界中的每个人都有这种想要的习惯
to test their code, why don't we create tools
为了测试他们的代码 我们为什么不创建工具
that make it a little easier to do so?
这会让你更容易做到这一点吗？
And in fact, there is a mechanism for doing
事实上 有一种机制可以让你
this, whereby we can use a tool that's popularly called pytest.
这就是说 我们可以使用一种通常被称为“最高测试”的工具
So pytest is a third party program that you can download and install
所以PYTEST是一个第三方程序 你可以下载和安装
that will automate the testing of your code, so long as you write the tests.
这将自动测试代码 只要您编写测试即可
But what's nice about this library and others
但这个图书馆和其他图书馆有什么好的
like it is that it adopts some conventions so
就像它采用了一些惯例 所以
that you don't have to write as many lines of code yourself manually.
您不必自己手动编写那么多行代码
They do some of that automatically for you.
他们会自动为你做一些这样的事情
Now this is a third party library.
这是一个第三方图书馆
There's other libraries for unit tests, so to speak,
可以说 还有其他用于单元测试的库
that is testing units of your code.
测试你的代码单元
Some of them come with Python itself.
其中一些是由Python本身提供的
We're proposing that we look at pytest today
我们建议今天就来看看pytest
because it's actually a little simpler than the unit
因为它实际上比单位更简单
testing frameworks that come with Python itself.
测试Python自带的框架
And what do we mean by unit testing?
单元测试是什么意思？
Unit testing is just a formal way of describing testing
单元测试只是描述测试的一种形式化方法
individual units of your program.
你的程序的单个单元
What are those individual units?
这些个体单位是什么？
They're typically functions.
它们是典型的函数
So unit tests are typically tests for functions that you have written.
因此 单元测试通常是对您编写的函数的测试
Now what does this mean in practice here.
这在实践中意味着什么
Let me go back to my VS code here and let
让我回到我的VS代码
me propose that we simplify my test calculator significantly.
我建议我们大大简化我的测试计算器
I'm going to go ahead and delete all of these tests, which were accumulating
我要删除所有这些测试
to like 31 lines of code.
喜欢31行代码
And let's see if we can distill the tests to their essence, using pytest.
让我们看看我们是否可以使用pytest提取测试的本质
From my same calculator program, let me still import square.
从我的同一个计算器程序 让我仍然进口平方
So I do still need that line of code so that I
所以我仍然需要这行代码
can test that's specific function.
可以测试它的具体功能
Now I'm going to go ahead and define a function, just like I did before,
现在我要继续定义一个函数 就像我之前做的一样
as follows.
如下
I'm going to define a function called test square, again
我将定义一个函数 叫做测试正方形
by convention, test underscore and the name of the function you want to test,
按照惯例 测试下划线和要测试的函数的名称
though it doesn't have to be that way.
虽然不一定非要这样
And now I'm going to go ahead and make a few assertions.
现在我要继续做一些断言
I'm going to assert that the square of 2 should equal 4.
我断言2的平方应该等于4
square of 3 should equal 9.
我断言3的平方应该等于9
I'm going to assert that the square of negative 2 should equal 4.
我断言负2的平方应该等于4
And I'm going to assert that the square of negative 3 should equal 9.
我断言负3的平方应该等于9
And lastly for now I'm going to assert that the square of 0 should equal 0.
最后 我将断言0的平方应该等于0
So I'm still using the assert keyword, as I introduced earlier.
所以我仍然使用assert关键字 正如我前面介绍的那样
And even though it was a little tedious to type those,
尽管打字有点乏味
it's only eight lines of code now.
现在只有八行代码了
And they're so easy to type.
它们很容易打字
It's not try and except and all of this.
这不是尝试和例外以及所有这一切
Wouldn't it be nice if something else, someone else,
如果其他的东西 其他的人
handled the try, the except, the printing, all of the standardization
办理了试车、排版、打印、所有标准化工作
of actually running these tests?
真的进行这些测试吗？
And that's where, indeed, pytest comes into play.
事实上 这就是PYTEST发挥作用的地方
Per the documentation for pytest, which can itself be installed with pip
根据pytest的文档 它本身可以与pip一起安装
install pytest, which we've used to install other libraries in the past,
安装PYTEST 我们过去用它来安装其他库
you can look at the documentation here for all of its formal usage.
您可以查看这里的文档 了解它的所有正式用法
But fortunately, pytest is pretty user friendly, as testing frameworks go,
但幸运的是 就测试框架而言 PYTEST是非常用户友好的
and it actually allows us to dive right in by just running pytest on the code
它实际上允许我们只需在代码上运行pytest就可以直接进入
that we've written.
这是我们写的
So if I go back to VS Code here and look at my test_calculator.py, which,
因此 如果我回到这里的VS代码 并查看我的test_culator.py
notice, has no main function anymore-- it has no conditional.
注意 不再有主函数--它没有条件
It has no tries.
它没有尝试过
It has no excepts.
它也不例外
It has no prints.
它没有指纹
It just has my few assertions-- pytest and other libraries
它只有我的几个断言--pytest和其他库
like it are going to automate the process of running these tests for me
就像它会自动为我运行这些测试一样
and informing me on the screen whether or not any of those tests failed.
并在屏幕上告诉我这些测试中是否有失败的
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续做这件事
I'm going to go ahead and increase the size of my terminal window
我将继续增加我的终端窗口的大小
for a moment, just so we can see more on the screen.
暂时 只是为了让我们能在屏幕上看到更多
And I'm going to run not python, as I've been doing.
我要运行的不是蟒蛇 就像我一直做的那样
I'm going to run pytest, which, again, is this third party
我将运行PYTEST 这也是第三方
tool for running tests in your code.
用于在代码中运行测试的工具
I'm going to run pytest of test_calculator, so that same file.
我将运行TEST_COMPUATOR的pytest 所以相同的文件
I'm going to cross my fingers as always and hit Enter,
我要像往常一样祈祷然后按回车键
and we'll see that something has failed.
我们会发现有些事情失败了
Now admittedly, even though I do think you'll
现在不得不承认 尽管我确实认为你会
find that pytest is relatively simple to use,
我发现pytest使用起来相对简单
it's output, at least at first glance, is not necessarily super user friendly.
它的输出 至少乍一看 不一定是超级用户友好的
So what are we seeing here?
那么我们在这里看到的是什么呢？
Notice at the very top of my window is the command that I ran after my prompt.
请注意 在我的窗口的最顶部是我在提示符后运行的命令
Right below that is a single F in red, which means fail,
就在它的正下方是一个红色的F 意思是失败
so not very encouraging.
所以并不是很鼓舞人心
I tried really hard here, but fail is my grade on this program.
我在这里真的很努力 但不及格是我在这个项目上的分数
But let's see exactly what happened.
但让我们来看看到底发生了什么
If I look at this excerpt here under failures,
如果我看一下这段失败的节选
you'll see that test square is the function that failed.
您将看到 测试正方形是失败的函数
That makes sense, because that's the only one I wrote.
这是有道理的 因为这是我唯一写的
And you'll see here somewhat arcane output describing what the error was.
您将在这里看到一些晦涩难懂的输出 描述错误是什么
So what you're seeing here is the first line of output equals equals 4,
所以你在这里看到的是第一行的输出等于4
which is fine.
这很好
There's no red error message below that, so that one's OK.
下面没有红色错误消息 所以这一条是正常的
But this line of code here assert that square of 3 equals equals 9,
但这行代码断言3的平方等于9
pytest did not like that assertion, because it didn't end up being true.
皮斯特不喜欢这种断言 因为它最终并不是真的
In fact, per the red E at the start of this line,
事实上 根据这行开头的红色E
you'll see that I'm effectively trying to assert that 6 equals equals 9.
你们会看到 我实际上是在试图断言6等于9
Now, where did the 6 come from?
现在 这6个人是从哪里来的？
Wait a minute, if my test involves this, notice that where 6 equals square of 3,
等等 如果我的测试涉及到这一点 注意6等于3的平方
this is saying that because I've called square, passing in a value of 3,
这就是说 因为我调用了Square 传入了值3
it turns out it's return value is 6.
结果是它的返回值是6
And of course, mathematically, 6 does not equal equal 9.
当然 从数学上讲 6不等于9
So that's why this is failing.
这就是为什么这一计划失败了
Now, pytest is not as user friendly as telling you
现在 PYTEST并不像告诉你的那样用户友好
exactly why the bug is there or how to fix it.
究竟为什么会有漏洞 或者如何修复它
This is really just a clue to you what must be wrong.
这真的只是一个线索 告诉你肯定是哪里出了问题
What you're seeing here is a clue that the first test passed,
你在这里看到的是第一次测试通过的线索
because there's no red error below that line of code, but this test failed.
因为该行代码下面没有红色错误 但该测试失败了
Somehow or other, your square function is returning 6
不知何故 您的平方函数返回6
when passed in 3 instead of 9.
当传入3而不是9时
So at this point, you sort of put your detective hat on,
所以在这一点上 你可以戴上你的侦探帽子
you go back to your actual code, and you think
您返回到您的实际代码 然后您认为
about in calculator.py, how in the world is
关于culator.py 世界上到底是怎样的
line 7 of my square function returning 6 instead of 9.
我的Square函数的第7行返回6而不是9
And at this point, odds are the light bulb
在这一点上 很可能是灯泡
would go off above your head proverbially,
会飞到你头上 这是众所周知的
and you would see, I'm using addition, instead of multiplication.
你们会看到 我用的是加法 而不是乘法
But what pytest has done for us is automate
但PYTEST为我们做的是自动化
the process of at least pointing out that error for us.
至少为我们指出这个错误的过程
And if I now go in and fix this-- let me go ahead,
如果我现在进去解决这个问题--让我继续
and the light bulb has gone off.
灯泡也熄灭了
I change the plus to a multiply.
我把加号改成乘号
Now I'm going to go ahead, and after clearing my screen,
现在我要继续 在清空我的屏幕后
I'm going to run not Python, but pytest of test_calculator.py,
我要运行的不是Python 而是test_culator.py的pytest
crossing my fingers again.
再一次为我祈祷
And now it's green.
现在它是绿色的
And I see just a dot, which indicates that my one and only test passed.
我只看到一个点 这表明我唯一的一次测试通过了
I'm good, 100% success with my test now after fixing that bug.
我很好 在修复了那个错误后 我的测试现在100%成功
Let me pause here and see if there's any questions.
让我在这里暂停一下 看看有没有什么问题
SPEAKER 3: So my question is, what if a user,
演讲者3：所以我的问题是 如果用户
instead of, because we are taking input from the user,
而不是因为我们从用户那里获取输入
what if the user is somewhat malicious and types in a string instead
如果用户有点恶意 而是输入了一个字符串 该怎么办
of an integer, or maybe he types in a float or some other data type?
或者他输入的是浮点数或其他数据类型？
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so what if the user, like we've
David Malan：是的 如果用户 像我们这样
seen in past examples, types in cat, instead of a number, when
在以前的示例中看到 在以下情况下 键入cat 而不是数字
we're expecting an integer?
我们要的是一个整数吗？
How do we test for something like that?
我们怎么测试这样的东西呢？
At the moment, I'm admittedly not testing user input.
目前 我诚然不是在测试用户输入
If I go back to my code here, notice that my calculator function, of course,
如果我回到这里的代码 请注意我的计算器功能 当然
has the square function that we keep testing and retesting.
具有我们不断测试和重新测试的平方函数
But notice that all of the user input is currently
但请注意 所有用户输入当前都是
relegated to my main function.
被降级为我的主要职责
And admittedly, as of now, I am not testing my main function.
诚然 到目前为止 我并没有测试我的主要功能
So there could be one of those bugs.
所以可能有一种虫子
And in fact, there would be, because if the user types in a string, like cat,
事实上 会有的 因为如果用户输入一个字符串 就像猫一样
instead of an integer, like 2 or 3, then line two recall would actually
而不是像2或3这样整数 那么第二行调用实际上将
raise a value error exception.
引发值错误异常
So we've seen that before.
所以我们以前见过这种情况
So when it comes to testing your code, this
因此 在测试代码时 这一点
is actually a good reason for having multiple functions in your program.
实际上是在程序中拥有多个函数的一个很好的理由
Rather than putting all of your logic in just the file itself,
与其将所有的逻辑都放在文件本身中
rather than putting all of the logic in just main,
与其把所有的逻辑都放在Main里
it's actually really good, really helpful practice
这实际上是非常好的 非常有帮助的练习
to break your ideas up into smaller bit-sized functions
将你的想法分解成更小的函数
that themselves are testable.
他们自己是可测试的
And what do I mean here?
我在这里是什么意思？
Square is perfectly testable.
Square是完全可测试的
Why?
为什么？
Because it takes as input a parameter called n,
因为它接受名为n的参数作为输入
and it returns as output in integer, which is going
并且它以整数形式返回输出 这是
to be the square thereof, hopefully.
希望能成为正方形
It has a well-defined input and a well-defined output.
它有一个定义良好的输入和一个定义良好的输出
It is therefore completely within your control in your test program
因此 在测试程序中它完全在您的控制之下
to pass in those values.
来传递这些值
Now I will say, if you want to test whether square behaves properly
现在我要说的是 如果您想测试Square是否正常运行
when passed something like a string, like, quote, unquote,
当传递类似字符串的东西时 比如 引号 不引号
"cat," we could absolutely do something like this,
“猫” 我们绝对可以做这样的事情
assert that the square of quote, unquote, "cat,"
断言引号的平方 不引号 “猫 ”
it's not going to equal something.
它不会等于某些东西
You can actually, using different syntax,
您实际上可以使用不同的语法
assert that a specific exception will be raised.
断言将引发特定的异常
So if we were actually going to go back into our square function,
所以如果我们真的要回到平方函数
improve it, and deliberately raise an exception, we could test for that too.
改进它 并故意引发异常 我们也可以测试这一点
But for now, I'm deliberately only testing the square function.
但现在 我故意只测试平方函数
I'm not testing for specific user input.
我不是在测试特定的用户输入
But that's another problem to be solved.
但这是另一个需要解决的问题
Other questions now on unit tests?
现在关于单元测试的其他问题？
SPEAKER 4: Do use the unit test to test code for the CS50 check?
演讲者4：是否使用单元测试来测试CS50检查的代码？
DAVID MALAN: So Check 50 is similar in spirit.
大卫·马兰：所以Check 50在精神上是相似的
Check 50 is a tool that we, CS50, wrote that is essentially doing something
Check 50是我们CS50编写的一个工具 它本质上是在做一些事情
like pytest for the evaluation of students' code.
比如为了评估学生的代码而使用的PYTEST
It is similar in spirit, but think of Check 50
它在精神上是相似的 但想想支票50
as being an alternative to pytest, if you will.
如果你愿意的话 可以把它当做一种替代品
But it works a little bit differently.
但它的工作原理略有不同
But same idea, pytest and unit testing more
但是相同的想法 最快测试和单元测试更多
generally is a technique that is independent of CS50
通常是一种独立于CS50的技术
and is something that you can and should be doing on your own code, both in
和是您可以也应该对您自己的代码执行的操作 无论是在
or outside of this class.
或者在这门课之外
How about one other question here on our unit tests?
我们的单元测试中还有一个问题呢？
SPEAKER 5: My question is that is instead
演讲者5：我的问题是
of writing four times, like as a square of, 2 squared 4,
四次写字 就像2的平方和4的平方
instead of that, can we write equals to in square brackets the numbers we want,
取而代之的是 我们能不能把我们想要的数字写在方括号中
instead of writing four lines?
而不是写四行？
DAVID MALAN: A really good question, absolutely.
大卫·马兰：绝对是一个非常好的问题
Right now if I go back to test_calculator.py,
现在 如果我返回到test_culator.py
it's indeed pretty manual.
这确实是相当手动的
It took me a while to say and to type out those several lines,
我花了一段时间才说出并打出了这几行字
and you could imagine writing some kind of loop to just assert in a loop
您可以想象编写某种类型的循环来在循环中断言
that this equals that, that this equals that, and so forth, using a list
这个等于那个 这个等于那个 以此类推 使用一个列表
or using maybe a list or a dictionary or some structure like that.
或者使用列表、词典或类似的结构
So yes, you can absolutely automate some of these tests
因此 是的 您完全可以自动执行其中的一些测试
by not just doing the same thing again and again.
而不是一遍又一遍地做同样的事情
You can still use all of the syntax of Python to do loops.
您仍然可以使用Python的所有语法来执行循环
But generally speaking, your tests should be pretty simple.
但总的来说 您的测试应该非常简单
And in fact, let me propose that we improve upon even this design further,
事实上 让我建议我们进一步改进这个设计
because at the moment what's not really ideal, when I run all of these tests
因为目前 当我进行所有这些测试时 情况并不理想
when my function is buggy, is notice the output that I got.
当我的函数出现错误时 请注意我得到的输出
Let me reintroduce that same bug by changing my multiplication back
让我通过更改我的乘法来重新引入相同的错误
to addition.
为了加法
Let me increase the size of my terminal window again.
让我再次增加终端窗口的大小
And let me run pytest again of test_calculator.py.
让我再次运行test_culator.py的pytest
So this is the version of my code now that has the bug again.
这就是我现在的代码版本 它又有了这个错误
So I'm going to see that big massive failure where
所以我会看到一场巨大的失败
this failure has been displayed to me.
这一失败已经向我展示了
But this is not as helpful as it could be,
但这并不像它可能的那样有帮助
because I have all of those other tests in my code.
因为我的代码中有所有这些其他测试
Recall that I had, what, one, two, three, four, five separate tests,
回想一下 我有 一 二 三 四 五个不同的测试
and I'm only seeing the output of the first.
我只看到了第一个的输出
Now, why is that?
为什么会这样呢？
If we go back to my code here, you'll see
如果我们回到我这里的代码 你会看到
that the first assertion that's failing, namely this one here, that assert
第一个失败的断言 也就是这里的这个断言
of square of 3 equals equals 9, the other tests aren't even getting run.
3的平方等于9 其他测试甚至没有运行
And that's not a big deal in the sense that my code is buggy, so one or more
这并不是什么大事 因为我的代码有错误 所以一个或多个
of them are probably going to fail anyway,
他们中的一些人可能无论如何都会失败
but wouldn't it be nice to know which of them are going to fail?
但是 知道他们中的哪些人会失败 不是很好吗？
And in fact, it's ideal to run as many tests all at once as possible
事实上 一次运行尽可能多的测试是理想的
to give you as many clues as possible to finding your bug.
给你尽可能多的线索来找到你的虫子
So let me propose that we improve the design of my testing code
所以让我建议我们改进我的测试代码的设计
now, still using pytest as follows.
现在 仍然使用pyest 如下所示
Instead of having one big function called test_square
而不是使用一个名为test_square的大函数
that tests the entire function itself with so many different inputs,
它用这么多不同的输入来测试整个函数本身
let's break down my tests into different categories.
让我们把我的测试分成不同的类别
And here, too, there's no one right way to do this.
在这里 也没有一种正确的方法来做到这一点
But my mind is thinking that I should maybe
但我的头脑在想 也许我应该
test positive numbers separately, test negative numbers separately, and test 0
分别测试正数 分别测试负数 并测试0
separately.
分开的
I could think of other ways.
我可以想出其他办法
I could test even numbers.
我可以测试偶数
I could test odd numbers or maybe some other pattern altogether,
我可以测试奇数或者其他模式
but separating this big test into multiple tests
但将这一重大测试分成多个测试
is probably going to yield more clues for me when something goes wrong.
可能会在出问题的时候给我提供更多线索
So let me do this.
那就让我来做吧
Let me go ahead and rename this function to test positive initially,
让我继续并将此函数重命名为初始测试阳性
and let me include in that function only those first two tests.
让我在这个函数中只包含前两个测试
Let me then create another function here called test negative.
然后 让我在这里创建另一个函数 称为测试负值
And in this function, let me test only negative 2 and negative 3.
在这个函数中 我只测试负2和负3
Then down here, let me do one more def of test_zero,
然后在这里 让我再定义一次test_Zero
and I'll just run one test in there.
我只会在那里做一次测试
So I have the same assertions, the same five,
所以我有同样的断言 同样的五个
but I've now divided them up among three separate functions.
但我现在将它们划分为三个不同的函数
What's nice about pytest and other unit testing frameworks
PYTEST和其他单元测试框架有什么优点
is that all three of these test functions will be run automatically.
这三个测试功能都将自动运行
Even if one of them fails, the others will be attempted.
即使其中一个失败了 其他的也会尝试
That means that if one or two or three of them fail,
这意味着如果他们中的一个或两个或三个失败了
I'll have one or two or three clues now for helping me find that mistake.
我现在有一条、两条或三条线索来帮助我找出那个错误
So let me go ahead and again increase the size of my terminal window,
因此 让我继续并再次增加我的终端窗口的大小
just so we can see more on the screen.
只是为了让我们能在屏幕上看到更多
My calculator still has the bug, using addition, instead of multiplication.
我的计算器仍然有错误 使用加法 而不是乘法
Let me go ahead and run not Python, but again, pytest of test_calculator.py,
让我们继续运行 不是运行Python 而是再次运行test_culator.py的pytest
crossing my fingers as always, and now, oh my God,
一如既往地祈祷 现在 哦 我的上帝
there's even more errors on the screen.
屏幕上的错误甚至更多
But this in itself is more helpful.
但这本身就更有帮助
Let's work through them from top to bottom.
让我们自上而下地学习它们
So under FAILURES here, in all caps, which
所以 在这里失败的情况下 大写的
I know is not very encouraging to see failure when you're just
我知道看到失败并不是很令人振奋
trying to solve a problem, but that's what these frameworks do,
试图解决一个问题 但这就是这些框架所做的
under FAILURES, the first function that failed is test_positive.
在FAILES下 第一个失败的函数是TEST_PRECTIVE
But here, too, we see the same clue as before.
但在这里 我们也看到了与以前相同的线索
The first one, 2, the square of 2 equals equals 4, that one is fine.
第一个 2 2的平方等于4 那一个很好
It's not erring with any red errors.
它不会有任何红色错误
But the next one is failing.
但下一次失败了
So I know that square is broken when I pass in 3.
所以我知道当我传到3的时候 正方形是被打破的
What about down here?
那下面呢？
It looks like, unfortunately, my test negative function is failing too.
不幸的是 看起来我的测试阴性功能也失败了
Why?
为什么？
When I pass in-- oh, this is interesting-- here now, negative 2
当我进入时--哦 这很有趣--现在 这里是负2
doesn't even work.
都不管用了
So I got lucky with positive 2.
所以我幸运地得到了正2
But negative 2 isn't working.
但负2不起作用
So that's a bit of a clue.
这是一个小小的线索
But in total, only two tests failed.
但总体而言 只有两次测试失败
So notice at the very bottom, this summary, two failed and one passed.
所以请注意 在最下面 这个总结 两个失败 一个通过
What's the other one?
另一个是什么？
What was the third one?
第三个是什么？
Test zero.
测试零
So test zero is passing.
因此 测试零正在通过
These two are failing.
这两家公司都在失败
And so that kind of leads me logically, mathematically, if you will,
因此 如果你愿意的话 这可以从逻辑上、数学上引导我
to the source of the bug.
找到了病毒的源头
And just to be clear too, if you have a lot of tests,
我也要说清楚 如果你有很多测试
this little one line output is helpful, even though also a bit discouraging,
这一小行输出是有帮助的 尽管也有点令人沮丧
fail, fail, and dot means pass.
FAIL、FAIL和圆点表示通过
So there are the three tests just depicted
所以有刚才描述的三个测试
graphically a little bit differently.
在图形上有一点不同
Let me rewind now and go back in to calculator.py.
现在让我回过头来 回到culator.py
Let's fix that bug, because let's suppose
让我们修复这个错误 因为让我们假设
that I've deduced I'm using addition.
我已经推断出我在使用加法
I should have been using multiplication all this time.
我应该一直在用乘法
Let me now after fixing the bug yet again,
现在让我在修复错误之后再一次
let me go back to my big terminal.
让我回到我的大航站楼
Let me run pytest of test_calculator.py, hitting Enter, crossing my fingers now,
让我运行test_culator.py的pytest 按Enter键 现在祈祷
and dot dot dot means all is well.
圆点表示一切都很好
100% of my tests passed, all three of them.
我所有的测试都通过了 三次都通过了
So now I'm good.
所以现在我很好
It doesn't necessarily mean that my code is 100% correct.
这并不一定意味着我的代码是100%正确的
But it does mean that it has passed 100% of my current tests.
但这确实意味着它已经100%通过了我目前的测试
And so it would probably behoove us to think a little harder about maybe
因此 我们应该更认真地考虑一下
we should test bigger numbers.
我们应该测试更大的数字
Maybe we should test even smaller numbers.
也许我们应该测试更小的数字
strings or something else.
也许我们应该测试一下字符串或其他东西
The onus is ultimately on you to decide what you're going to test.
最终的责任是你来决定你要测试什么
But in the real world, you're going to be very unhappy with yourself
但在现实世界中 你会对自己非常不满意
or someone else-- maybe your boss is going to be very unhappy with you--
或者其他人--也许你的老板会对你非常不满意--
if you did not catch a bug in your code, which you could have caught
如果你没有在你的代码中发现一个错误 你可能已经发现了
had you just written a test to try that kind of input.
您是否刚刚编写了一个测试来尝试这种输入
Let me pause again and see if there's any questions now
让我再暂停一次 看看现在是否有任何问题
on unit testing with pytest.
关于使用pytest进行单元测试
SPEAKER 6: So if you wanted to test, like someone suggested before,
演讲者6：所以 如果你想测试 就像之前有人建议的那样
user input as well as testing your function,
用户输入以及测试您的功能
do you do that within the same file?
您是否在同一文件中执行此操作？
Or do you make separate files for different types of tests?
或者 您是否为不同类型的测试创建单独的文件？
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
大卫·马兰：这个问题问得很好
You could absolutely make separate files to test different types of things.
您绝对可以创建单独的文件来测试不同类型的东西
Or if you don't have that many, you can keep them all in the same file.
或者 如果您没有那么多 您可以将它们都保存在同一个文件中
At the moment, I've been storing all of my tests in one file for convenience,
目前 为了方便起见 我一直将我所有的测试存储在一个文件中
and there's not terribly many of them.
而且它们的数量也不是很多
But we'll take a look in a bit at an example
但我们将通过一个例子来了解一下
that allows me to put them into a folder and even run pytest
这样我就可以把它们放到一个文件夹里 甚至运行pytest
on the whole folder of tests as well.
在整个测试文件夹上也是如此
So that's possible.
所以这是可能的
Other questions on unit testing.
关于单元测试的其他问题
SPEAKER 7: So I've got two questions.
演讲者7：我有两个问题
So a couple of while ago, you just used an exception called--
几年前 您刚刚使用了一个名为--
I'm not sure what it was-- oh yeah, assertion error.
我不确定这是什么--哦 是的 断言错误
What exactly does that particular error catch?
这个特定的错误到底捕捉到了什么？
And my second question is, does the assert keyword
我的第二个问题是 Assert关键字
stand out to the compiler, exactly tell them
站在编者面前 准确地告诉他们
to insert this particular line of code?
来插入这行特定的代码？
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
大卫·马兰：确实如此
The assert keyword we're seeing and the assertion error we saw earlier
我们看到的ASSERT关键字和前面看到的断言错误
are intertwined.
是交织在一起的
So when you use assert and the assertion fails,
因此 当您使用Assert而断言失败时
because whatever Boolean expression you're using is not true, it's false,
因为无论你用的是什么布尔表达式 都不是真的 而是假的
an assertion error, by definition of Python, will be raised.
根据Python的定义 将引发断言错误
So those two work in conjunction.
因此 这两者是协同工作的
Those errors, those assertion errors, are still being raised by my code
那些错误 那些断言错误 仍然由我的代码引发
here when any of these lines of code fail.
在这里 当这些代码行中的任何一行失败时
However, pytest, this third party library,
然而 PYTEST这个第三方库
is handling the process of catching those exceptions automatically for me,
正在为我处理自动捕获这些异常的过程
so as to give me this standard output.
以便给我这个标准的输出
So we started today's story by really implementing unit testing myself.
因此 我们从自己真正实现单元测试开始了今天的故事
I wrote all of the code myself.
所有的代码都是我自己写的
I wrote main.
我写了Main
I did my conditional.
我做了我的附带条件
I did try and except.
我确实试过了 除了
Honestly, it's going to get incredibly painful to write tests
老实说 编写测试将变得非常痛苦
long term if you and I have to write that much code every time, especially
长期而言 如果你和我每次都要写那么多代码 特别是
when our function is this small.
当我们的功能这么小的时候
So pytest and unit testing frameworks like it just automate so much of that.
因此 PYTEST和类似的单元测试框架可以自动完成很多工作
Essentially, pytest adds the try, the except, the if, the prints for you,
本质上 PYTEST为您添加了try、Except、If和指纹
so you can just focus on the essence of the test, which
因此 您可以只关注测试的本质 即
really are these inputs and outputs.
真正的是这些输入和输出
How about time for one other question here on unit testing as well?
这里还有一个关于单元测试的问题 你觉得呢？
SPEAKER 8: So when we enter minus x or minus 5 squared,
演讲者8：所以当我们输入-x或-5的平方时
square root of that number comes up.
这个数字的平方根就出来了
But when we put 6.6 or 5.6, something like that integer,
但当我们把6.6或5.6放入这个整数时
then line shows error.
则行显示错误
So what's happening there?
那么那里发生了什么呢？
DAVID MALAN: So I'm deliberately testing integers right now,
大卫·马兰：所以我现在故意测试整数
in large part because I only want pow to operate on integers.
很大程度上是因为我只想让POW对整数进行运算
And that might be conveyed in Python's documentation or my own documentation
这可能会在Python的文档或我自己的文档中传达出来
for that function.
来完成这项任务
If you were to pass in something else, like a float,
如果你要传递其他东西 比如一个花车
it turns out that floating point values in Python and other languages
事实证明 Python和其他语言中的浮点值
are actually very hard, if not impossible,
实际上非常困难 如果不是不可能的话
to represent 100% precisely.
以100%准确地代表
And so if you are trying to compare it against some other value,
因此 如果你试图将其与其他价值进行比较
there might be slight rounding errors as a result.
因此 可能会有轻微的舍入误差
I'm just inferring from what you've described,
我只是根据你所描述的推断
but I'm very deliberately now testing this function with only the inputs
但我现在非常有意地测试这个函数 只使用输入
that I would expect.
这是我所期待的
It might indeed throw other errors if other inputs are passed.
如果传递了其他输入 它确实可能抛出其他错误
Allow me to propose that we consider what should happen if square
请允许我提议我们考虑一下如果双方达成协议
isn't actually passed a number.
实际上并没有传递一个数字
For instance, if I go back to calculator.py,
例如 如果我返回到culator.py
and suppose that I, or perhaps someone else using my square function,
假设我 或者其他使用平方函数的人
simply forgets to convert the return value of input from a str to an int,
只是忘记将输入的返回值从字符串转换为整型
as by modifying line to here.
例如 将行修改为此处
Now, something's definitely going to go wrong if I type in a str
现在 如果我输入一个字符串 肯定会出错
instead of what appears to be an int.
而不是看起来是整型的
For instance, if I clear my terminal here,
例如 如果我在这里清除我的终端
run Python of calculator.py and hit Enter--
运行culator.py的Python并按Enter--
let's type in cat as our value for x-- and of course,
让我们输入cat作为x的值--当然
this raises now a type error.
这现在引发了一个类型错误
Why?
为什么？
Can't multiply sequence by non-int of type 'str.'
不能将序列与类型为‘str.’的非int相乘
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
You can't do cat times cat, because indeed, square is
你不能做猫乘以猫 因为事实上 正方形是
expecting that end will be some number.
期待这一结局的将是一些数字
But that doesn't necessarily mean that square itself is buggy.
但这并不一定意味着Square本身就有漏洞
But this does mean that if I expect a type error to be raised,
但这确实意味着 如果我预计会引发类型错误
let's test for that too, so that I know the behavior indeed works as expected.
让我们也对此进行测试 这样我就知道行为确实像预期的那样工作
So let me go back to test_calculator.py, and let me go in add a fourth test down
因此 让我回到test_culator.py 然后添加第四个测试
here.
这里
How about define test underscore, and I'll
定义测试下划线如何 我将
call this test_str, because I'm going to specifically and deliberately pass
将其称为test_str 因为我将明确而有意地通过
in a str for testing.
在用于测试的字符串中
And I want to in spirit assert that passing in something like cat to square
我想在精神上断言 像猫对方这样的传球
will raise a type error.
将引发类型错误
But we don't use the assert keyword for that.
但是我们没有使用ASSERT关键字
Rather, we need this.
相反 我们需要这个
Let me go to the top of this file, and let me additionally
让我转到此文件的顶部 并让我另外
import the pytest library itself, because it turns out
导入pytest库本身 因为它被证明
there's a function in that library called
在该库中有一个名为
raises that allows me to express that I expect an exception to be raised.
引发 这使我能够表示我希望引发异常
And I can express that as follows with pytest.raises,
我可以用下面的pytest来表达这一点
and then in parentheses I can pass in the type of exception I expect,
然后在括号中 我可以传递我期望的异常类型
which is going to be a type error in this case.
在这种情况下 这将是一个类型错误
And now when do I expect that type error to be raised?
现在 我应该在什么时候引发该类型错误呢？
Whenever I do something like calling square and passing in not a number,
每当我做一些事情 比如调用Square 而不是传入数字时
but something like cat.
但有点像猫
So now if I go back to my terminal window,
所以现在如果我回到我的终端窗口
run pytest of test calculator.py, this time having four tests,
运行测试计算器.py的pytest 这一次有四个测试
I should see that all four now are successful.
我应该看到现在所有四个都是成功的
Let's now consider how we could test code that doesn't just expect numbers
现在让我们考虑如何测试不只是期望数字的代码
as input, but actually strings.
作为输入 但实际上是字符串
And let me rewind us in time here in VS Code
让我在VS Code中及时回顾一下
to that very first program we wrote a few different versions of in hello.py
对于第一个程序 我们编写了几个不同版本的in hello.py
that ultimately looked a little something like this.
它最终看起来有点像这样
I had a main function that prompted the user
我有一个主功能 可以提示用户
for the value of a variable by asking them, "what's your name?"
通过问他们“你叫什么名字？”来获取变量的值
question mark.
问号
And then we went ahead and did something like hello,
然后我们继续前进 做了一些类似于打招呼的事情
open paren, name, passing that user's name into a function called hello.
打开Paren name 将该用户名传递给一个名为Hello的函数
Now that function hello recall ultimately looked like this.
现在函数Hello recall最终看起来是这样的
We defined hello as taking a parameter called to,
我们将Hello定义为接受一个名为to的参数
the default value of which was world, and that function very simply
其缺省值为World 且该函数非常简单
printed hello, followed by a comma, and then whatever
打印问候 后跟逗号 然后什么都行
the name that had been passed in.
已传入的名称
And then we ultimately called main, but for now onward,
然后我们最终调用了Main 但现在开始
I'm going to always add this if conditional,
如果有条件 我会一直加上这一点
if name equals equals underscore underscore main, then and only then
如果名称等于等于下划线Main 则仅当
do I want to call main.
我要不要给Main打电话
So that's essentially what this program looked like in its last incarnation.
所以这基本上就是这个程序在上一次化身中的样子
How do we go about testing it?
我们该如何进行测试呢？
Here again too, I'm not going to test the user's input per se in main.
在这里 我也不打算在main中测试用户的输入本身
I'm going to focus really on the module of code
我将真正集中在代码模块上
here that's of interest, which is the hello function itself.
这就是我们感兴趣的 这就是Hello函数本身
How can I go about testing the hello function?
我如何开始测试Hello函数？
Unfortunately, even if I start by doing something like code of test hello.py--
不幸的是 即使我开始做一些类似于测试hello.py的代码--
let me go about and start writing a test program--
让我开始着手编写一个测试程序--
I could import from my hello program a function called hello.
我可以从我的Hello程序中导入一个名为Hello的函数
So a bit strange to see from hello import
所以从问候导入中看到有点奇怪
hello, but notice that on this line here, I'm importing from the module--
您好 但是请注意 在这一行 我是从模块导入的--
that is the file called hello.py-- the function called hello.
这就是名为hello.py的文件--名为Hello的函数
And how do I go about testing this?
我该如何进行测试呢？
If I have a function like define test_argument like this--
如果我有一个像定义测试参数这样的函数--
let me do this.
让我来做吧
So if I were to define a function like define test_hello, what could I do?
那么 如果我要定义一个函数 比如定义TEST_HELLO 我该怎么办呢？
I could call hello with quote, unquote, say, "David,"
我可以用引号 不带引号 说“大卫”来打招呼
and then check if it equals, what, "hello, David."
然后检查它是否等于 “你好 大卫 ”
So would this work, this approach here?
那么 这种方法在这里行得通吗？
If I've written a test, called test_hello, that
如果我已经编写了一个名为test_Hello的测试 那么
calls hello with an argument of David and then tests its return value,
使用david参数调用Hello 然后测试其返回值
just like we've done for our calculator, would this work as written?
就像我们对我们的计算器所做的那样 这会像写的那样工作吗？
And let me go back to in just a moment the version
让我稍后回到这个版本
of hello that we're testing.
我们正在测试的问候
So you can see that function hello.
所以你可以看到函数Hello
Here's the test.
这就是测试
Here is the actual code.
以下是实际的代码
Would this test now work?
这项测试现在会奏效吗？
Any thoughts?
有什么想法吗？
SPEAKER 9: I think the problem is that in the first version in hello.py,
演讲者9：我认为问题在于 在hello.py的第一个版本中
you're using the to argument that you first declared, when you declared
您使用的是您第一次声明的to参数 当您声明
the function instead of using the name.
函数 而不是使用名称
DAVID MALAN: That is actually not a bug here.
大卫·马兰：这在这里实际上不是一个错误
So let me stipulate that in hello.py, this code actually
所以让我规定在hello.py中 这段代码实际上
does work as intended.
确实如预期的那样工作
And let me go ahead and test it manually, just to demonstrate as much.
让我继续手动测试 只是为了演示一下
Let me run Python of hello.py, typing in, as my name, D-A-V-I-D, and I see,
让我运行hello.py的Python 输入我的名字D-A-V-I-D 我看到了
in fact, that it says, "hello, David."
事实上 它是在说 “你好 大卫 ”
If, though, I were to change this program,
不过 如果我改变这个计划
and get rid of the name argument, get rid of the name variable,
去掉name参数 去掉name变量
and just call hello, again, running Python of hello.py,
然后再次调用Hello 运行hello.py的Python
this time I'm not even prompted, because I got rid of my input call,
这一次我甚至没有得到提示 因为我摆脱了我的输入电话
but it does behave as I expect.
但它的表现确实符合我的预期
It does say "hello, world."
它确实在说“你好 世界 ”
So let me stipulate that this code in its current form is actually correct,
因此 让我规定当前形式的代码实际上是正确的
but my test is not going to work as I'd hoped.
但我的测试并没有像我希望的那样奏效
And there's a subtle difference between my hello function
我的Hello函数之间有一个细微的区别
and my square function that explains.
我的平方函数可以解释
Why might this test not work as intended?
为什么这项测试可能不会像预期的那样有效？
SPEAKER 10: Because it's not returning a value.
演讲者10：因为它没有返回值
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
大卫·马兰：是的 确实如此
Recall our discussion early on about functions.
回想一下我们早先关于函数的讨论
Functions can either return a value, like my square function hands
函数可以返回值 就像我的方形函数Hands
you back the square of some value, or they
你支持有一定价值的平方 否则他们
can have side effects, sort of visual artifacts
可能会有副作用 一种视觉假象
that might happen on the screen, like printing something out on the screen.
这可能会发生在屏幕上 就像在屏幕上打印一些东西一样
And by definition, that's how print works.
根据定义 这就是印刷品的工作方式
Notice that hello, it is short, but it's implemented ultimately
注意Hello 它很短 但它最终实现了
using the print function, which does not return a value as I'm using it here.
使用print函数 该函数并不像我在这里使用的那样返回值
It instead has this side effect of printing something onto the screen.
相反 它的副作用是将一些东西打印到屏幕上
So it is not correct in my test function to check
所以在我的测试函数中检查是不正确的
if the return value of hello equals equals hello David,
如果Hello的返回值等于Hello David
because again, hello is not returning anything.
因为再说一次 Hello不会返回任何内容
It's printing something, that side effect,
它是在打印一些东西 那种副作用
but notice, literally, it has no return keyword,
但请注意 从字面上看 它没有Return关键字
unlike my square function, which did.
不像我的平方函数 它做到了
So here's an opportunity to perhaps change
所以这是一个或许可以改变的机会
how I go about implementing my actual functions.
我是如何实现我的实际功能的
It turns out that as your programs get more and more sophisticated, more
事实证明 随着您的程序变得越来越复杂 越来越
and more complicated, it tends to be best practice not
更复杂的是 最好不要
to have side effects if you can avoid it,
如果你能避免的话会有副作用
especially if you want your code to be testable.
尤其是如果您希望您的代码是可测试的
And in fact, I'm going to propose that we change my hello program to now work
事实上 我将建议我们更改我的Hello程序以使其正常工作
as follows.
具体如下
Let me go ahead and change this function to not print hello and then that name.
让我继续更改该函数 不再打印问候和姓名
Let me go ahead and literally return maybe
让我继续下去 也许真的会回来
an F string, which will clean this up a little bit, hello comma
一个F字符串 它将使这一点变得更清楚 你好逗号
to close quotes at the end.
在结尾用引号结束
So my syntax here is just the familiar f string or format string.
所以我这里的语法就是熟悉的f字符串或格式字符串
It's going to return hello, world or hello, David or hello, whomever's name
它将返回Hello、World或Hello、David或Hello 不管是谁的名字
is passed in as that argument, but I'm returning it now.
作为该参数传入 但我现在返回它
I'm not printing it out.
我不会把它打印出来的
So what needs to change up here?
那么 这里需要改变的是什么呢？
I could do something like this.
我可以做这样的事
I could say something like output equals hello
我可以这样说 产出等于你好
and then print output in my main function.
然后在我的Main函数中打印输出
Or I can simplify that, because I don't really need that variable.
或者我可以简化它 因为我并不真的需要这个变量
I could instead just do this.
我可以干脆这么做
I could still call hello, but I could immediately print out the result.
我仍然可以打个招呼 但我可以立即把结果打印出来
And this version of my hello program now is actually more testable.
现在 我的Hello程序的这个版本实际上更易于测试
Why?
为什么？
Because these assert statements that we're using,
因为我们使用的这些断言语句
and we've seen thus far for our tests, are really
到目前为止我们的测试 真的是
designed to test arguments into functions and return values
旨在测试函数中的参数并返回值
they're from, not testing side effects.
它们来自 不是测试副作用
So if you're doing equals equals, you're looking for a return value, something
所以如果你做的是等于 你在寻找一个返回值
that's handed back from the function.
这是从函数返回的
So that's fine.
所以这很好
If I modify the design of my program now not to just print hello,
如果我现在修改我的程序设计 不只是打印问候
but to return the string, the sentence, the phrase that I want to construct,
但要返回我想要构建的字符串、句子和短语
I can leave it to the caller--
我可以把它留给打电话的人--
that is the function who's using this hello function--
这就是使用Hello函数的函数--
to handle the actual printing.
来处理实际的打印
Now what does this mean in my code?
这在我的代码中意味着什么？
It means now if my hello.py looks like this,
这意味着如果我的hello.py看起来像这样
and hello is indeed returning a value, in my test_hello function,
在我的test_Hello函数中 Hello确实返回了一个值
I can test it exactly like this.
我可以完全像这样测试它
So let me go ahead and run pytest of test_hello.py,
因此 让我继续运行test_hello.py的pytest
crossing my fingers as always, and voila, one passed.
像往常一样 我的手指交叉 瞧 一个过去了
So I passed this test, because apparently the return value of hello
所以我通过了这项测试 因为显然Hello的返回值
does indeed equal "hello, David."
确实等于“你好 大卫 ”
Let's test the other scenario.
让我们测试另一个场景
What if I call hello without any arguments?
如果我在没有任何参数的情况下调用Hello会怎么样？
Let's assert that calling hello with nothing in those parentheses
让我们断言 在这些括号中没有任何内容的情况下呼叫Hello
similarly equals hello comma, but world, the default value.
类似地 等于问候逗号 但世界 缺省值
Let me now go ahead and run pytest of test_hello.py.
现在让我继续运行test_hello.py的pytest
And that too passes entirely.
而这也完全过去了
But there too, suppose that I had made some mistakes.
但在这一点上 假设我犯了一些错误
Suppose that there were a bug in my code.
假设我的代码中有一个错误
It might not be best practice to combine multiple tests in this one function,
在这一个函数中组合多个测试可能不是最佳实践
so let's make it more clear what might pass or fail.
因此 让我们更清楚地知道什么可能通过 什么可能失败
Let's call the first function test the default to this function.
让我们调用第一个函数来测试此函数的缺省值
And let's only include this first line of code.
让我们只包含这第一行代码
And then let's go ahead and define another function, like test_argument,
然后让我们继续定义另一个函数 比如test_argument
to test this other line of code here.
来测试这里的另一行代码
So now I have two different tests, each of which
所以现在我有两种不同的测试 每一种
is testing something a little fundamentally different.
正在测试一些从根本上不同的东西
So now when I run my code, it's still not broken.
所以现在当我运行我的代码时 它仍然没有损坏
If I run pytest of test_hello.py, Enter, I've now passed two tests.
如果我运行test_hello.py的pytest 输入 我现在已经通过了两个测试
And that's just as good as before.
这和以前一样好
But if I did have a bug, having two tests instead of one
但如果我真的有缺陷 有两次测试而不是一次
would indeed give me, perhaps, a bit more of a hint as to what's wrong.
或许会给我更多一点关于哪里出了问题的提示
Questions now on this testing of return values,
现在关于返回值测试的问题
when these return values are now strings instead of integers
当这些返回值现在是字符串而不是整数时
and why we've done this?
我们为什么要这么做？
SPEAKER 11: So my question is about function inside the function.
演讲者11：所以我的问题是关于函数内部的函数
Can we test that too or recursion we haven't seen?
我们能不能也测试一下 或者我们还没见过的递归呢？
DAVID MALAN: If you have a recursive function, which we've not
David Malan：如果你有一个递归函数 我们还没有
discussed in this class, yes, you can absolutely
在这节课上讨论过的 是的 你绝对可以
test those too by simply calling them exactly in this way.
也可以通过简单地以这种方式调用它们来测试它们
Recursion does not affect this process.
递归不会影响此过程
How about one more question here on unit tests
下面是关于单元测试的另一个问题
before we look at one final example?
在我们看最后一个例子之前？
SPEAKER 12: When testing our arguments, can we
演讲者12：在检验我们的论点时 我们可以
use something like loops or inside of assets or for the values?
使用循环之类的东西 还是在资产内部使用 或者用于价值？
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely.
大卫·马兰：当然
You can absolutely use a loop to test multiple values.
您绝对可以使用循环来测试多个值
In this case, for instance, I could do something like this.
例如 在这种情况下 我可以做这样的事情
I could say for name in the following list of Hermione, say, Harry, and Ron,
我可以在下面赫敏的名单上说出名字 比如说 哈利和罗恩
I could then within this loop assert that hello of that given name equals
然后 我可以在这个循环中断言给定名称的Hello等于
equals, say, the format string of hello, comma name,
等于 比方说 Hello、逗号名称、
and then run all of these here at once by running, again,
然后在这里一次运行所有这些 再次运行
pytest of test_hello.py.
Test_hello.py的pytest
It's still going to be just one test within that function,
这仍然只是该功能中的一项测试
but if there's something interesting about those several strings that
但如果这几根弦有什么有趣的地方
makes it compelling to test all of them, you can absolutely
使得测试所有这些功能变得很有说服力 您完全可以
automate the test in that way.
以这种方式自动执行测试
With that said, each of your tests should ideally
也就是说 理想情况下 您的每一项测试都应该
be pretty simple and pretty small.
要非常简单 也要非常小
Why?
为什么？
Because you don't want to write so much code,
因为你不想写太多代码
so much complicated code that your tests might be flawed.
如此复杂的代码 以至于您的测试可能存在缺陷
What we don't want to have to do is write tests for our tests and test
我们不想做的是为我们的测试和测试编写测试
for our tests for our test, because it would never end.
为了我们的测试 因为它永远不会结束
So keeping tests nice and simple is really the goal,
因此 让测试保持良好和简单才是真正的目标
so that a reasonable human, yourself included,
所以一个有理智的人 包括你自己
can eyeball them and just claim, yeah, that is correct.
可以盯着他们看 然后声称 是的 这是正确的
We don't need tests for our tests.
我们的测试不需要测试
How about one other feature?
还有一项功能呢？
Suppose that we don't have just one test, but many different tests instead,
假设我们不只有一项测试 而是有许多不同的测试
and we want to start to organize those tests into multiple files and even
我们希望开始将这些测试组织到多个文件中 甚至
a folder.
一个文件夹
Pytest and other frameworks support that paradigm as well.
Pytest和其他框架也支持这一范例
In fact, let me go ahead and test hello.py using a folder of tests,
事实上 让我继续使用测试文件夹测试hello.py
with technically just one test, but it would
从技术上讲只有一次测试 但它会
be representative of having even more in that folder.
代表那个文件夹里有更多的东西
I'm going to go ahead and create a new folder called test
接下来 我将创建一个名为test的新文件夹
using mkdir at my command line.
在我的命令行中使用mkdir
And then within that folder, I'm going to go ahead and create a file called
然后在该文件夹中 我将继续创建一个名为
test_hello.py.
Test_hello.py
Within this file, meanwhile, I'm going to test the same thing.
同时 在这个文件中 我将测试相同的东西
So I'm going to go ahead, and from hello, import hello.
所以我将继续 从Hello开始 导入Hello
And I'm going to go ahead and define a function like test default that
接下来 我将定义一个类似于测试默认设置的函数
simply tests the scenario where hello with no arguments
简单地测试不带参数的Hello的场景
returns hello, comma world.
返回您好 逗号世界
And I'm going to have that other function where
我将拥有另一个功能 即
I test that an argument is passed.
我测试是否传递了一个参数
And in this case, I'll choose an argument
在这种情况下 我会选择一个论点
like asserting that hello, quote, unquote, David,
比如断言 你好 引用 引用 大卫
equals, indeed, hello, comma, not world, but David.
等于 确实 你好 逗号 不是世界 而是大卫
So in this case, I've just recreated the same test as earlier,
因此 在这个例子中 我刚刚重新创建了与前面相同的测试
but they're in a file now in a folder called test.
但它们现在位于一个名为TEST的文件夹中
Pytest allows me to run these here too.
PYTEST也允许我在这里运行这些程序
But to do so, I actually need to create one other file.
但要做到这一点 我实际上需要创建另一个文件
Within my test directory, I need to create a file called __init__.py,
在我的测试目录中 我需要创建一个名为__init__.py的文件
which has the effect, even if this file is empty,
它的效果是 即使这个文件是空的
of telling Python to treat that folder as not just a module, but a package,
告诉Python不仅要将该文件夹视为一个模块 还要将其视为一个包
so to speak.
可以这么说
A package is a Python module or multiple modules
包是一个或多个Python模块
that are organized inside of a folder.
它们被组织在一个文件夹内
And this file, __init__.py, is just a visual indicator to Python that indeed
而这个名为__init__.py的文件只是一个可视指示器 用于指示Python确实
it should treat that folder as a package.
它应该将该文件夹视为一个包
If I had more code in this folder, I could do even more things
如果这个文件夹中有更多的代码 我可以做更多的事情
with this file.
用这份文件
But for now, it's just a clue that it's indeed
但就目前而言 这只是一个线索 表明它确实是
meant to be a package and not just a module or file alone.
意味着是一个包 而不仅仅是一个模块或文件
What I can now do in closing is run pytest, not even on that specific file,
最后 我可以做的是运行pytest 而不是在该特定文件上运行
but on a whole folder of tests.
而是一大堆测试
So if I run pytest of test, where the test is the name of that folder,
因此 如果我运行pytest of test 其中test是该文件夹的名称
pytest will automatically search through that folder looking
PYTEST将自动搜索该文件夹 查找
for all possible tests, granted there's just those two in this one file,
对于所有可能的测试 假设只有这两个人在这个文件中
but when I run it now with Enter, I'll still pass those tests.
但是 当我现在用Enter键运行它时 我仍然可以通过这些测试
I'll still get 100%.
我还是会拿到100%的
And I now have a mechanism, ultimately, for testing my own code.
最终 我现在有了一种机制来测试我自己的代码
So whether you're writing functions that return integers or something else,
因此 无论您是在编写返回整数的函数还是其他函数
functions that have side effects that could be rewritten as functions
具有可重写为函数的副作用的函数
that return values, you now have a mechanism
返回值 您现在就有了一种机制
to not just wait for, one, someone like us to test your code
不仅仅是等待 一个 像我们这样的人来测试你的代码
and not just test your code manually again and again, which
而不仅仅是一次又一次地手动测试代码 这
might get tedious, and you might make mistakes
可能会变得单调乏味 你可能会犯错误
by not including some possible inputs, we now
通过不包括一些可能的输入 我们现在
have an automated mechanism for testing one's own code that's
有一种自动机制来测试自己的代码 这是
going to be even more powerful when you start collaborating with others
当你开始与他人合作时 你会变得更加强大
so that you can write tests that ensure that if they
这样您就可以编写测试 以确保如果它们
make a change to the same code, they haven't broken the code that you've
更改相同的代码 他们还没有破解您已经破译的代码
written.
写的
That's it for this week.
本周就到这里吧
We'll see you next time.
我们下次再见